https://www.alltech.com/privacy-policy-and-terms-use

Search
Social MediaFacebookTwitterYouTubeLinkedInInstagramAlltech BlogPodcastLocations
Breadcrumb
Home
Privacy Policy and Terms of Use
Thank you for visiting our website. We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting personal data that you share with us at this website. This privacy policy informs you about how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from) and gives you important information about your privacy rights.
This privacy policy explains how we protect and use the personal data that we collect at this website. Information included in this policy is designed to explain why we collect your personal data, how we access and use it, and how we store it to keep it safe. Please read this privacy policy before using the website or submitting any personal data here.
Who is Alltech and why does Alltech have a Privacy Policy posted here?
Founded in 1980 by Irish entrepreneur and scientist Dr. Pearse Lyons, Alltech discovers and delivers solutions for the sustainable nutrition of plants, animals and people. With expertise in yeast fermentation, solid state fermentation and the science of nutrigenomics, Alltech is a leading producer and processor of yeast additives, organic trace minerals, feed ingredients, premix and feed.  Alltech, Inc has its global company headquarters located at 3031 Catnip Hill Road, Nicholasville, Kentucky 40356, USA, as well as a European headquarters located at All-Technology (Ireland) Limited Alltech Bioscience Centre, Summerhill Road, Sarney, Dunboyne Co. Meath. Alltech collects and stores the personal data you share at this website. Alltech may share your personal data internally to  other members of the Alltech Group and with its service providers who assist Alltech with providing you specific services.
Alltech Inc (“the Company”) is made up of different legal entities, which all form part of a wider group of companies (“the Alltech Group”) details of which can be found here. This privacy policy is written on behalf of the Alltech Group.  When we mention "Alltech ", "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy policy, we mean the relevant company in the Alltech Group responsible for processing your data. This privacy policy applies to all Alltech websites and companies that link to or reference this Privacy Policy.
Is it possible to get additional information about privacy policies related to other Alltech websites?
If you would like to view additional information on our privacy policies that are related to other Alltech websites or affiliated privacy statements, please click the privacy policy links on the respective websites  for these notices or affiliated statements.
Does Alltech have to collect personal data by law?
We will ask for your consent before we collect your personal data for specific purposes.  In general, we collect data only for the purpose of website analytics. We do not use IP addresses to identify individual users. When we are required to collect personal data by law or regulation in order to perform a specific service or provide to you a specific product, we will need your consent before we can perform the related service or provide you with the product you have contracted with us to receive. When we enter into a contract with you, you can expect that our contract with you will include information about how we protect your privacy.
Does Alltech follow privacy and data protections like the GDPR?
Alltech uses all reasonable efforts to process data in accordance with the laws of the countries in which we operate, including the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation. (GDPR) We take appropriate measures to protect the personal data you provide to Alltech. Personal data includes any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person or data subject.
What happens if Alltech changes the way it protects my personal data?
If we make changes in our practices to further enhance the way we protect your personal data, we will update this policy and post the update at this website.  In some situations we may also email the updated policy to you. Please review the privacy policy whenever you visit Alltech’s website to make sure that you understand how any personal data you provide will be used.
What data subject rights apply to users of Alltech websites?
Users of Alltech websites have the right to: Access their data, to have Alltech correct their data, the right of data portability, and the right to have Alltech delete their data at any time. Users also have the right, and the ability, to manage their Alltech subscriptions at any time.
Users of Alltech websites have the right to:
Request access to the personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request") that Alltech has about you.
Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This right allows you to request that Alltech correct incomplete or inaccurate data Alltech holds about you.
Request erasure of the personal data that we hold about you. This right allows you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which we will tell you about, if applicable, at the time of your request.
Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or the legitimate interest of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms.
Request a transfer of your personal data to a third party.
Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
How do we collect your data?
We use different methods to collect data from you and about you including through:
Direct interactions. You may give us your [Identity and Contact] by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
inquire about our products or services;
create an account on our website;
subscribe to our service or publications;
request marketing materials to be sent to you;
enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
give us feedback or contact us.
Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our website, we automatically collect technical data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, which we explain in further detail in our cookie policy.
For what purpose do we collect your data?
The personal data you share with us allows us to answer your inquiries and/or to deliver to you any marketing emails and e-newsletters to which you subscribe. It also provides us the information we need to contact you in agreement with the consent that you give to us when your personal data is collected. We do not use your personal data for automated decision-making or profiling.
Alltech will only use your personal data for purposes that are consistent with and related to the original reason why we collected your personal data. If you wish for an explanation about how the processing we are doing is related to the original purpose for which your personal data was collected, please contact us.
If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and either seek your additional consent or will explain to you why we are legally required to use your personal data in the specific situation.
Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.
Some examples of personal data that we collect are grouped together as follows:
Identity Data includes [first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, and title].
Contact Data includes [billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers].
Transaction Data includes [details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us].
Technical Data includes [internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, and other technology on the devices you use to access this website].
Profile Data includes [your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses].
Usage Data includes [information about how you use our website, products and services].
Marketing and Communications Data includes [your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences].
We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health, or genetic and biometric data). We do not collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.
Alltech obtains contact details and other personal information regarding media contacts and influencers from a variety of sources including Cision. If you wish to know more about how such information is collected and used, please refer to Cision’s privacy notice at https://www.cision.com/us/legal/privacy-policy/.
Can this website be accessed without sharing personal data?
You can access many of the pages on our website without giving us your personal data. Where you have the option to provide personal data through the website, like providing your email or home address, by submitting your personal information, you consent to our use of the data as we have described in this privacy policy and in the privacy statements that appear on the forms through which you submit your personal data.
In what location does Alltech process personal data?
Alltech is the data controller of the personal data we collect. Alltech uses a data processing service (data processor) provider in some instances to process your personal data. When Alltech uses a data processing service, the data processor is required by contract to have appropriate measures in place to protect personal data. The data processor processes the data only within the scope of Alltech’s instructions, and in accordance with the laws of the European Union. It is possible that your personal data may be stored outside of the European Union, namely in the United States. Data processors working with Alltech are contractually obligated to protect personal data in accordance with the laws of the European Union regardless of their location.
How long do we keep your personal data?
Alltech retains the personal data you submit in order to answer your inquiries and/or to deliver any marketing emails and e-newsletters to which you subscribe. If you request that we end your subscription(s), Alltech will retain the personal data submitted for one year for the preparation of statistics and for processing your comments and questions. We will use this retention approach unless you tell us that you do not wish for Alltech to keep this information for this time period. Alltech will delete your information at your request. Alltech may also be required to share personal data with legal authorities but will only do so if it is legally required.
What do I do if I want to stop receiving marketing messages from Alltech?
You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links included on marketing messages sent to you or by contacting us at any time at privacy@Alltech.com.
When you opt out of receiving marketing messages, we will honour your request by no longer sending you marketing messages. We will still use your personal data if we have it as a result of a product/service purchase, warranty registration, product/service experience or other transactions. We retain your personal information in situations like those described so that we can continue to provide you services relating to these transactions.
How can I contact Alltech’s Data Privacy team to ask questions or request information relating to my rights as a data subject?
You may contact Alltech if you require access to your personal data, or if you require your information to be corrected or deleted.  You may also lodge a complaint with the Alltech Data Privacy team or ask any other data related query. Please contact them at privacy@alltech.com.
Cookie Policy (Separate) Notice- Pop Up on Website when user hits website
How do I understand and utilize the cookies on this website?
A cookie is a small file made up of letters and numbers stored (with your consent) on your browser or the hard drive of your computer.  Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive. Cookies allow us to identify you (or, more accurately, your computer) when you visit our website.
When you visit our website, our server will automatically record certain information about your visit such as your IP address, browser type and version, time zone setting, full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our site; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and the time and duration of your visit.
Cookies and tracking technology are useful for gathering information such as browser type and
operating system, tracking the number of visitors to the Site, and understanding how visitors
use the Site. Cookies can also help customize the Site for visitors. Personal data
cannot be collected via cookies and other tracking technology; however, if you previously
provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information.
Details about the cookies we can be found HERE.
Loading...
